Emmanuel Ofori Mensah

Computer Scientist

(929)377-3831 • New Jersey Mannyom98@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-mensah-81b5b719b

Summary

I am a recent graduate from Rutgers University with a Bachelor of Science degree in computer science. Proficient in data analysis and reporting using computer software, with excellent time-management skills and strong written and oral communication abilities. Experienced in programming languages, problem-solving, research, and project design. Committed to continuous learning and growth, with a passion for technology and innovation.

Education

Rutgers University - Camden, NJ

September 2019- January 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Cum Laude with Honors

Employment

Amazon Fulfillment Center, West Deptford, NJ

Fulfillment Associate 1

June 2020 – Current

- Scanned, sorted, labeled, and monitored package flow through the facility.
- Trained new employees to help adapt to the fast-paced environment.
- Troubleshot and resolved issues.
- Worked in a team to meet productivity goals.
- Maintained a clean and organized work area.

Oigetit Fake News Filter,

Quality Assurance Analyst Intern

July 2022 – October 2022

- Monitored software performance and quality for improvement.
- Built and implemented software to interpret and collate data.
- Prepared reports and presented to software development team for bug resolution.
- Participated in special projects and meetings for application improvement.

Inductotherm Corp, Rancocas, NJ

IT Systems Engineer Intern

May 2019 – August 2019

- Managed and monitored systems and infrastructure.
- Installed, configured, tested, and maintained operating systems and applications.
- Proactively ensured high availability of systems.
- Wrote custom scripts for efficiency and automation.
- Provided technical support for the user community.

Extracurricular

National Honor Society

2022 – Present

Skills

- Microsoft Suite
- Java
- HTML & XML
- Python
- Windows
- Linux

- Customer Service
- Attention to detail
- Problem-Solving
- Manual Test
- Troubleshooting
- Analytical and Critical Thinking

Certificate

Palo Alto Networks Assessment-Based Certificate